<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Innovation on Locus: Richard Careaga</title>
    <link>/tags/innovation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Innovation on Locus: Richard Careaga</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/innovation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of R Cookbook, 2nd Ed.</title>
      <link>/2019/08/24/review-of-r-data-cookbook-2nd-ed/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/08/24/review-of-r-data-cookbook-2nd-ed/</guid>
      <description>There is a whole sub-culture of food porn, the lavish coffee table books that set out to educate you to an entire culture through its food. I once saw a library of several hundred.
These are page flippers – doesn’t that look marvelous, we’ll have to try it next time we find halibut cheeks. The sad fact, though, is that any of these books are lucky if the owner actually uses one or two of its recipes and exalted if a recipe becomes a dinner party staple.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>eDiscovery is pattern recognition and eyeballs are expensive</title>
      <link>/2019/06/03/ediscovery-is-pattern-recognition-and-eyeballs-are-expensive/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/06/03/ediscovery-is-pattern-recognition-and-eyeballs-are-expensive/</guid>
      <description>Clients are transforming their businesses with the tools of data science. How long do you suppose they will pay $50/hour for humans to read tons of ediscovery?
The legal profession owes a great debt to the 19th century mathemetician Georg Boole whose work became the genesis of the boolean algebra that every lawyer is familiar through the use of keyword searches. For decades, it has helped us wade through more than we could read.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commercial data science: a parable of downsides of crisp deployment</title>
      <link>/2018/11/08/commercial-data-science-a-parable-of-downsides-of-crisp-deployment/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/11/08/commercial-data-science-a-parable-of-downsides-of-crisp-deployment/</guid>
      <description>Narcocorridos are a Mexican musical genre celebrating the drug trafficking culture. As you can read in wiki, it has a surprisingly long history and is popular despite official attempts to suppress it.
Stay with me, there’s a parable here about R, Python, DevOps, Bias Toward Action and leaving change on the table, in two senses.
A mild English flavor of a narcocorido is Townes van Zandt’s ballad Pancho and Lefty, his best known work in the pre-pop Country genre.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>